2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com
E: info@sralocum.com
P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



CURRICULUM VITAE

SRA Locum Template

It is of importance that all our CVs are received in the same format. We appreciate if you could fill this template out and return to info@sralocum.com. Should you have any questions please contact: Shahid Ali, Locum Coordination Consultant, SRA Locum (00353 1 685 4700).

Dr. Ayesha Ahmed

Cork, County Cork Nationality: British

Professional Summary

A dedicated medical practitioner, experience in medicine and in surgery. Excellent communication skills, as demonstrated with senior doctors, supervisors, teachers, lecturers, colleagues, fellow students and when liaising with the patients. Has extensive medical skills to identify areas of focus or concern, able to produce relevant and meaningful conclusions and develop these into recommendations to bring about the necessary outcomes or changes. An extremely self-motivated, disciplined and confident individual. Excellent presentation and interpersonal skills. Good team work experience, able to priorities clinical needs, organise ward round and work well under pressure.

Core Qualifications & Skills

Experience in history taking and clinical examination
Arterial blood gas sampling and interpretation
Insertion of naso-gastric tube &
cannula Plain X-ray interpretation
ECG placement and interpretation
Preparation and checking of key medical equipment for
procedures Qualified in administering drugs and medication
Confident in welcoming patients and conducting initial consultations
Knowledge of the laboratory and administrative processes in the medical arena
Excellent organisational skills, precise timekeeping, able to prioritise and
manage own diary Excellent all-round IT skills and quick to learn new skills
Accurate medical record keeper

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com
E: info@sralocum.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



Experience

Date	Grade	Area
40 104 122	NA - I' I CUO	added Berteral Hearth Berteries
18/01/22	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
30/10/21	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
02/10/21	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlanise
15/09/21	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
01/09/21	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
22/08/21	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
13 & 14/08/21	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
06 & 07/07/21	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
19/06/21 16/06/21	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlagise
09/06/21	Medical SHO Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
		Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
17 – 19/05/21 15 &16/05/21	Medical SHO Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
		. ,
06 & 07/04/21 29 & 30/03/21	Medical SHO Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
15/19/22/26/02/21 - 04 & 22	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
- 31/03/21	ivieuicai 300	iviidiand Regional Hospital, Portidoise
08/02/2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
03/02/2021 - 05/02/2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital, Portlaoise
03/02/2021 - 03/02/2021	IVIEUICAI SHU	iviidiand negional nospital, Portiadise

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper,

Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com

E: info@sralocum.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



SHO A&E, CUH, Cork, January'21 – To Date

Assess patients that enter the emergency room immediately and oversee emergency patient's recovery

Conduct follow-up visits to monitor the patient's condition

Request the appropriate medical tests and based on them, follow a treatment plan Develop effective patient care plans

Refer patients to the appropriate specialists

Ensure that patients are stable before transferring them to the proper department for further evaluation

Provide instructions for discharge and any relevant

paperwork Maintain the patient's medical records

Coordinate with different ER departments to ensure patients receive the necessary treatment

SHO Radiation Oncology, CUH, Cork, November'20 - January'21

Providing safe and effective care of patients

Conducting tests and examinations to confirm diagnoses

Executing radiation treatments such as stereotactic radiosurgery

Developing treatment plans which compromise the appropriate therapeutic techniques and drug dosages to be administered

Consistently monitoring patients' progress

Providing diagnosis and treatment for all categories of patient in the department

Providing pharmacological treatment and suggesting appropriate lifestyle changes

Clinical Attachment, Northampton General Hospital, UK, 2019

Ward rounds under supervision

Observed consultations

Participated in patient administration

Taken patient histories

Performed IV cannulation (under direct supervision)

Physical examinations (under direct supervision)

Observed surgery procedure

House Officer, Trauma & Orthopaedics Surgery, Abbasi Shaheed Hospital, Karachi, July'2014 – September'2014

Reviewed all patients in the wards and attended ward rounds
Ensured TTAs and EDNs are undertaken in a timely manner for patients being
discharged Ensured medical notes are updated daily
Reviewed all investigations undertaken on ward patients

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper,

<u>Dublin 4, D04 W7K5</u>

W: www.sralocum.com E: info@sralocum.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



Day to day management of all patients on the ward including non-orthopaedic patients Liaised with nursing staff with regards to medical concerns raised about patients

Assisted with out-patient clinics and in theatre

General duties included ward rounds, acting upon the treatment plan, cannulations and venepunctures, assessing and reviewing patients post ward rounds and reporting to the Specialty Registrar/Consultant

Presented in the weekly trauma meeting

House Officer, General Surgery, Abbasi Shaheed Hospital, Karachi, April'2014 – June'2014

Provided general surgical care in consultation with the consultants and other medical staff and provided care for all patients when on call

Attended new and follow up general surgery clinics

Performed procedures like cannulation, Foleys catheterization and N/G intubation Participated in weekly multi-disciplinary meetings Participated in theatre lists for elective and emergency patients Experienced in pre & post-operative care

Communicated and worked collaboratively with all members of the surgical team

House Officer, General Medicine, Sir Syed Hospital, Karachi, Oct'2013 – Mar'2013

Regular visited to wards to monitor and record patients' recovery status

Discussed various treatment options extensively with patients and families

Closely examined patients' medical history, medication allergies and physical condition

Maintained accurate medical records and document patient case history in detail

Continuously worked to improve performance at an individual and practice

level Educated patients regarding conditions and treatment options

Met with pharmaceutical representatives to learn about the latest medications
Provided volunteer medical care at local clinic and on quarterly medical charity trips
Carefully analysed test results and information gathered during examinations to
properly diagnose illnesses and diseases
Patiently explained prescribed procedures and discussed test results with patients and their families

Strictly maintained confidentiality of patients, families, colleagues and any sensitive situations

Certifications

The Professional and Linguistic Assessment Board UK (PLAB 1&2) – 2019

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com

E: info@sralocum.com P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



MRCOG Membership (Part 1) – Royal College of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists UK – 2016 Occupational English Language Test (OET) - B

Voluntary Work

Volunteer Doctor, Pakistan (Bi-Annual Medical Mission) - 2014

Part of a team that conducted research on the assistance available to physically challenged persons in rural areas, gave health talks to the institutionalised students and care givers

Volunteer Doctor, Pakistan (Bi-Annual Medical Mission) - 2013

Provided screening of diabetes and hypertension, and counselling services as required

Volunteer Doctor, Pakistan (Bi-Annual Medical Mission) - 2012

Participated in the diagnosis and management of medical, paediatric and gynaecological cases in rural outreaches

Education and Training

Bachelor of Medicine, Bachelor of Surgery (MBBS) – 2013

Sir Syed Collage of Medical Sciences for Girls, Karachi, Pakistan

Clinical Attachment - Plastic and Hand Surgery - 2013

Agha Khan University Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan

Clinical Attachment – A&E – 2013

Abbasi Shaheed Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan

Research

Prevalence of smoking in teenage - Research done in the department of community medicine - 2011

Courses

Evening Medical Updates – 2019 - To Date

Completed online BMJ learning modules of different medicine topics – 2018

Presentations

Case presentation on dysphagia

Diagnosis, surgical intervention, prognosis and quality of life in patients with Ca Rectum

Basal cell carcinoma: prevalence, diagnosis and intervention

Presentation on the management of electrolyte imbalances in Post- Operative patients

References will be furnished upon request